eyejot.com 2008-12-17

# Eyejot :: Privacy Policy

### What This Privacy Policy Covers

This policy covers how Eyejot, Inc., a Washington corporation ("Eyejot," "we," "us," or "our"), and all of its affiliated websites, products and services, including, without limitation, www.eyejot.com and Eyejot (collectively, the "Eyejot Sites, Products and Services"), treat personal information that the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services collect and receive. Personal information is information about you that is personally identifiable like your name, address, email address, or phone number, and that is not otherwise publicly available. Please note that any posting made while using the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services is not considered "personal information" and is not considered the type of information protected by a privacy policy. 

This policy covers how the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services deal with information about your children under the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act ("COPPA"), and how parents and legal guardians may request from us how they can review, delete or stop the collection of the personally identifiable information of their child. This policy does not apply to the practices of companies that Eyejot does not own or control, or to people that Eyejot does not employ or manage. 

Eyejot, Inc. is a licensee of the TRUSTe Web Privacy Seal Program. TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices. This privacy statement covers the Web site www.eyejot.com. Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe. 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact us at [support@eyejot.com](mailto:support@eyejot.com). If you do not receive acknowledgement of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns. 

### Information We Gather

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services may collect personal information (such as your name, email address) when you register with them or use the particular products. We collect this information in order to register you for our services and to communicate to you for service related reasons. 

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services may automatically receive and record information on our server logs from your browser, including your IP address, cookies, and the pages you request. 

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services use information for the following general purposes: products and services provision, billing, identification and authentication, services improvement, contact, research, and anonymous reporting. We will not sell, share or rent your information with any third parties unless as otherwise disclosed in this privacy statement. 

### IP Address

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services may occasionally obtain IP addresses from users depending upon how you access our web sites. IP addresses, browser and session information may be used for various purposes, including to: 

  * Diagnose and prevent service or technology problems reported by our users or engineers that are associated with the IP addresses controlled by a specific web company or ISP. 
  * Estimate the total number of users visiting Eyejot's web sites from specific geographical regions. 
  * Help determine which users have access privileges to certain content, services or resources that we offer. 
  * Monitor and prevent fraud and abuse. 

### Cookies

A cookie is a small amount of data, which often includes a unique identifier that is sent to your web browser from a web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. These data are associated with your web browser and are often stored in an area that you can inspect, modify and delete. You can also control whether your browser allows cookies to be set from the Eyejot web sites or platform. 

If you reject all cookies, you may not be able to use the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services that require you to "sign in," and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings. You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. 

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services use their own cookies for a number of purposes, including to: 

  * Require you to re-enter your password after a certain period of time has elapsed to protect you against others accidentally accessing your account contents. 
  * Keep track of preferences you specify while you are using the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services. 
  * Estimate and report our total audience size and traffic. 
  * Conduct research to improve the content and services provided on the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services. 

In the event that Eyejot lets other entities show advertisements on some of our web pages, these other entities do not have access to Eyejot's cookies. 

### Web Beacons

This site uses [web beacons](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_bug) and other, related, tracking mechanisms to aid us in analyzing traffic to our site. We primarily utilize analytic tools provided to us by Google but may also enlist resources from other vendors. These tools give us a high-level overview of traffic patterns but do not reveal to us user-identifiable information. Additionally, this site may deliver ads that are managed and presented through third-party advertising distribution companies. These companies may also utilize web beacons and cookies to deliver semi-targeted messaging but are unable to collect existing account or other user identifiable information. 

### Information Use, Sharing and Disclosure

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services do not share personal information we learn about you from your use of the web sites, products and services with others except as described in this policy. We do not share your information with unrelated third parties for their direct marketing purposes. However, the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services may display targeted advertisements based on personal information. 

When you provide personal information through using the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services you are however sharing your personal information with Eyejot and its affiliated entities. The use of your personal information by these organizations is subject to this policy. We use an email service provider in order to deliver our email newsletter campaigns. We share your personal information with this service provider in order for them to deliver emails. They will never use your information for reasons other than what they are contracted to do and will not share your information with any other vendors. 

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services may use or share your personal information where it is necessary to complete a transaction, to operate or improve the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services, to do something that you have asked us to do, or tell you of products and services that we think may be of interest. 

When you want to add a friend to your contact list or invite them to a group, you will be asked to submit your friends email address to Eyejot. Eyejot will use this information in order to send your friend a one time email inviting them to our web site. We do not store this information unless your friend decides to register for our services. 

Where you are contacted with an offer or service based on information you have shared with any Eyejot Site, Product and/or Service, we will do our best to provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of receiving such further communications at the time you are contacted, however, in connection with any of our paid products and services (i.e., products or services that you license or use for a fee), we reserve the right to send you certain communications relating to those products and services, such as service announcements and administrative messages that are considered part of your Eyejot account, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them. If you decide to opt-out of receiving our promotional communications such as the Eyejot Newsletter, you may send us an email at [support@eyejot.com](mailto:support@eyejot.com) to unsubscribe. 

The Eyejot Sites, Products and Services may share personally identifiable information about you under the following circumstances: 

  * In the course of operating our business it may be necessary or appropriate for us to provide access to your personal information to others such as our service providers, contractors and select vendors so that we can operate the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services and our business. Where practical, we seek to obtain confidentiality agreements that are consistent with this policy and that limit others' use or disclosure of the information you have shared. 
  * We may share your personal information to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal process, to establish or exercise our legal rights or, defend against legal claims and if in our judgment in such circumstances disclosure is required or appropriate. 
  * We may share your personal information if we believe it is necessary in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our various terms of use, or as otherwise required by law. 

As we continue to develop our business, we may also buy or sell all or part of our business. In such transactions, personally identifiable information you have shared with us is generally one of the business assets that will be transferred. The transferred personally identifiable information will remain subject to the promises made in this privacy policy or subsequent policies to which you have consented. In these circumstances we will notify you of this business transition 30 days prior to the transaction taking place. 

If you use participate on our blog, linked through this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by others, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information, such as your email address, that you may choose to submit through blog submissions and comments and encourage you to refrain from revealing those details. 

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Eyejot may revise, modify or update this policy. We will notify you about significant changes in the way we treat personal information by sending a notice to the primary email address specified in your particular Eyejot account or by placing a prominent notice on our site. 

### Confidentiality and Security

No data transmissions over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Consequently, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make efforts to ensure security on our systems. We use physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect personal information about you. Your account information is password-protected. 

If Eyejot learns of a security systems breach we may attempt to notify you electronically so that you can take appropriate protective steps. By using the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services or providing personal information to us you agree that we can communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of those sites, products and services. We may post a notice on our applicable web sites if a security breach occurs. If this happens, you will need a web browser enabling you to view the applicable web sites. We may also send an email to you at the email address you have provided to us in these circumstances. Depending on where you live, you may have a legal right to receive notice of a security breach in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice) you should notify us at privacy@eyejot.com. 

### Changing your Preferences and Personal Information

You can edit your account information with an applicable Eyejot Site, Product and Service at any time. Most personal information you may provide is entirely optional. For example, to the extent that parents are considering whether to permit their children to use the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services, we do not condition a child's participation based upon their provision of any more personal information than is necessary to operate those sites, products and services. 

You can delete your applicable account by contact Eyejot's support team through email at [support@eyejot.com](mailto:support@eyejot.com); however, please note that some personal information, primarily your contact information, may remain in our records to the extent necessary to protect our legal interests or document compliance with regulatory requirements. The easiest way to access your information for the purpose of updating it is to visit your profile page. 

### Contacting Eyejot

If you have a privacy concern regarding any Eyejot Site, Product or Service, or this policy, and if you cannot satisfactorily resolve it through the use of those sites, products or services, you should complete a feedback form or you can write to us by email at [privacy@eyejot.com](mailto:privacy@eyejot.com). Alternatively, we can be reached at our postal mail address: 

> Eyejot, Inc.  
>  315 5th Avenue South, Suite 800  
>  Seattle, WA 98104  
>  Attention: Privacy Officer 

If you object to any sharing of your personal information that may be permitted under this policy, you may do so by writing us at the above address. We will take reasonable steps to accommodate your requests as they relate to our business practices. In some instances, honoring your requests may interfere with or preclude your ability to use the Eyejot Sites, Products and Services or may require us to terminate our relationship with you. 

Effective Date: December 20, 2007. Updated October 10, 2008.
